http://www.dcd.com/privacy-policy

×
You are already registered and logged in.
If you would like to upgrade to a paid subscription, please click here
×
Place holder for text1
You are already registered and logged in.
Place holder for link
×
It looks like your subscription is expired.Please call customer support at 800-533-5680
×
Access Denied ...
We're sorry, but access to the Conceptual Estimator is restricted to current, paid subscribers only.If you feel you are receiving this message in error, or if you would like to start a paid subscription, please call us at 1.800.533.5680.
Click here  to learn more about the Conceptual Estimator
×
You are not logged in.
You must be logged in and have a current,paid subscription in order to access the Conceptual Estimator.
Click here to login
×
Place holder for text5
You are already registered and logged in.
Place holder for link
×
Place holder for text6
You are already registered and logged in.
Place holder for link
×
User alert...
To continue reading, you must be subscribed and logged-in
Click here to sign up for a Free Subscription
×
Simpl•Est Unit Price
With Simpl•Est Unit Price , you get a complete estimating solution for just $12.95 a month and you can cancel at anytime.
You get full access to the online 2019 BNi General Construction Costbook along with a powerful search tool!
For over 30 years, the BNi General Construction Costbook has set the standard for accuracy in construction estimating.
Starting here ensures you don't overlook a single item.
You can click on any item in the book to add it to your estimate...
Just click on any item in the book to add it to your estimate.
It's automatically saved for you in the cloud.
You can change quantities, add comments and more.
Everything in your estimate is downloaded to an Excel spreadsheet where you fine tune your estimate and print a complete final report!
Sign up for Simpl•Est Unit Price now and get FREE unlimited access for a full month, plus a FREE digital subscription to DCD.
After that, continued access to Simpl•Est Unit Price is billed at just $12.95 a month. It's an incredible value for such a powerful estimating solution, but don't take our word for it ... try it for yourself - free!
×
Simpl•Est Square Foot
With Simpl•Est Square Foot, you get unlimited access to a cost database featuring nearly 2,000 actual building projects!
You get detailed cost-breakdowns for schools, hospitals, municipal buildings, offices, multi-family housing, restaurants, retail stores and much more.
And that's just the beginning!
Once you select a building category, you can then drill down on projects that match foundation types, roof types, interior and exterior wall types, and other criteria.
Then at the click of a mouse, you can add, change or delete cost items to suit YOUR projects specs.
You can also change the square foot size of the project, and even the project's location. Instantly you'll see the recalculated total project cost, along with all the cost details.
Simpl•Est Square Foot answers the question "How much will it cost to build?"
With Simpl•Est Square Foot you can run your own "What If" scenarios.
Check out the costs of different building types.
Get a reality check on a bidder's estimate.
Demonstrate the impact of a change order.
With Simpl•Est Square Foot you can estimate with greater confidence than ever before.
Try Simpl•Est Square Foot FREE for 30 days.
Just click the button below to get started right now.
We'll give you a full month to explore the power of Simpl•Est Square Foot.
Then if you wish to continue using Simpl•Est Square Foot, we will bill you just $14.95 a month.
Plus we'll send you a Free copy of the 2019 DCD Guide to Construction Costs (a $69.95 value).
Why wait?
If you do any kind of estimating work, you owe it to yourself to give Simpl•Est Square Foot a try.
×
Simpl•Est Unit Cost
With Simpl•Est Square Foot, you get unlimited access to a cost database featuring nearly 2,000 actual building projects!
You get detailed cost-breakdowns for schools, hospitals, municipal buildings, offices, multi-family housing, restaurants, retail stores and much more.
And that's just the beginning!
Once you select a building category, you can then drill down on projects that match foundation types, roof types, interior and exterior wall types, and other criteria.
Then at the click of a mouse, you can add, change or delete cost items to suit YOUR projects specs.
You can also change the square foot size of the project, and even the project's location. Instantly you'll see the recalculated total project cost, along with all the cost details.
Simpl•Est Square Foot answers the question "How much will it cost to build?"
With Simpl•Est Square Foot you can run your own "What If" scenarios.
Check out the costs of different building types.
Get a reality check on a bidder's estimate.
Demonstrate the impact of a change order.
With Simpl•Est Square Foot you can estimate with greater confidence than ever before.
Try Simpl•Est Square Foot FREE for 30 days.
Just click the button below to get started right now.
We'll give you a full month to explore the power of Simpl•Est Square Foot.
Then if you wish to continue using Simpl•Est Square Foot, we will bill you just $9.95 a month.
Plus we'll send you a Free copy of the 2019 DCD Guide to Construction Costs (a $69.95 value).
Why wait?
If you do any kind of estimating work, you owe it to yourself to give Simpl•Est Square Foot a try.
Click here to get started with Simpl•Est Square Foot
×
Try Simpl•Est Davis-Bacon FREE for 30 days.
Just log-in and then click the Try it Free button below to get started right now. We'll give you a full month to use Simpl•Est Davis-Bacon. Then if you wish to continue using it, we will bill you just $4.95 a month.Why wait? If you are responsible for hiring sub-contractors, you owe it to yourself to give Simpl•Est Square Foot a try.
×
Terms of Use
Welcome to the Design Cost Data website (dcd.com), owned by BNI Publications, Inc., a Design Cost Data Company ("BNi" or "DCD" or "we", or "us").
We are providing this content (including linked/connected eBooks, collectively the "eBook") and applications (such as Conceptual Estimator and Simpl•Est) as a service to those customers who have subscribed with us to access the content ("Subscriber(s)" or "you").
Please review the following rules ("Terms of Use") that govern your use of the eBook.
By using our eBook you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions set forth below, and our Privacy_Policy and all disclaimers or other terms and conditions that appear elsewhere on our eBook (collectively the "Agreement").
Your use of our content and/or applications constitutes your agreement to follow and be bound by the Agreement.
If you do not agree to be bound by the Agreement, you are not authorized to use our content.
We may revise the Agreement at any time for various reasons, and we strongly recommend that you visit these pages periodically in order to review the Agreement.
Although you are not required to review the Agreement each time you access the content (whether by choice or by electronically bypassing this page), your use of or clicking onto any portion or any page of our eBook nonetheless binds you to the Agreement.
Proprietary Rights.
Unless otherwise noted, all written and/or other materials that are part of our eBook, including information, images, illustrations, designs, icons, data, software, photographs, graphs, videos, typefaces, graphics, music, sounds and other material (collectively "Content"), are protected by copyright, trademark, patent or other proprietary rights, and these rights are valid and protected in all forms, media and technologies existing now or developed in the future.
Except as provided in Paragraph 2 below or authorized or licensed to Subscriber in writing, Subscriber may not copy, modify, remove, delete, augment, add to, publish, transmit, participate in the transfer or sale, lease or rental of, create derivative works from or in any way exploit any of the Content, in whole or in part.
All Content is copyrighted as a collective work under United States and international copyright laws, and as between Subscriber and BNi, BNi owns, to the fullest extent allowed by such laws, the copyright in the selection, coordination, arrangement, and enhancement of all Content.
The BNi trademarks, logos and other trademarks on our eBook are the property of their respective owners and are owned by, licensed to, or, where required, used with permission of BNi, and, as such, may not be reproduced, copied, or manipulated in any manner without the express, written approval of the trademark owner.
Your Use of the content.
The eBook and the Content are intended solely for use by one Subscriber working at one computer workstation ("Workstation").
You acknowledge and agree that the eBook may permit Subscriber to copy or download portions of the Content and/or other downloadable materials displayed on the eBook ("Excerpts"), but BNi may restrict or impose limitations on Subscriber's ability to copy or download Excerpts, in BNi's sole and absolute discretion.
With respect to such Excerpts, Subscriber agrees to leave intact all copyright, trademark and other proprietary notices contained in such material, and will not modify or alter the material or copy or post the material on any network computer or broadcast the material in any media whatsoever.
Subscriber may not modify, transmit, distribute, use or reuse, repost or "frame" the Content for public or commercial purposes without express written permission from an authorized representative of BNi.
No right, title or interest in any Content is transferred to the Subscriber as a result of the Subscriber's downloading or copying of an Excerpt.
Except as noted above, Subscriber shall not publish, transmit, distribute, display, modify, create derivative works from, sell or participate in any sale of or exploit in any way, in whole or in part, any of the Content, the eBook, Excerpts or any related intellectual property.
As a condition of using the eBook, Subscriber agrees that if BNi, in its sole and complete discretion, requests in writing that Subscriber remove any link or links to the eBook, Subscriber will promptly do so.
Subscriber further agrees that BNi may, in its sole and complete discretion and at any time, terminate Subscriber's access to and use of our eBook, or any part thereof, with or without notice to Subscriber.
Subscriber agrees not to tamper with our applications, misrepresent Subscriber's identity, conduct fraudulent or unauthorized activities in connection with our eBook, or use agents to do any of the same.
Subscribers are prohibited from violating or attempting to violate the security of our eBook, including, without limitation, (i) accessing the eBook from more than one Workstation at one time; (ii) providing Subscriber's access information to others, and/or allowing others to access the eBook using Subscriber's access information; (iii) accessing data not intended for such Subscriber or logging onto a server or into an account which the Subscriber is not authorized to access; (iv) using our eBook for unintended purposes or trying to change the behavior of our eBook; (v) attempting to probe, scan or test the vulnerability of the eBook; (vi) attempting to interfere with other Subscribers' access to the eBook, including without limitation via means of submitting a virus to our eBook, overloading, "flooidng," "spamming," "mailbombing" or "crashing"; (vii) forging communications on behalf of our eBook (impersonating our eBook), or to our eBook (impersonating as a legitimate Subscriber).
Sending unsolicited and unauthorized e-mail on behalf of BNi, including promotions and/or advertising of products or services, is expressly prohibited.
You agree not to use any device, software or routine or data to interfere or attempt to interfere with the proper working of our eBook or any activity being conducted on this eBook.
You agree, further, not to use or attempt to use any engine, software, tool, agent, data or other device or mechanism (including without limitation browsers, spiders, robots, avatars or intelligent agents) to navigate or search or remove Excerpts from our eBook other than the tool or tools provided by the eBook or by generally publicly available and acceptable Internet browsers.
If and when requested, you agree to provide true, accurate and complete Subscriber information to BNi.
NO WARRANTIES; LIMITATION OF LIABILITY.
YOUR USE OF AND RELIANCE UPON ANY AND ALL INFORMATION, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE CONTENT IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK.
SUCH INFORMATION IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" BASIS.
BNI MAKES NO EXPRESS OR IMPLIED REPRESENTATIONS, WARRANTIES, OR GUARANTEES WITH REGARD TO THE APPROPRIATENESS, ACCURACY, SUFFICIENCY, CORRECTNESS, VERACITY, VALUE, COMPLETENESS, OR TIMELINESS OF SUCH INFORMATION.
BNI EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.
IN NO EVENT SHALL BNI
AND/OR ITS AGENTS, EMPLOYEES OR SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF OUR EBOOK, WITH THE DELAY OR INABILITY TO USE OUR EBOOK OR RELATED SERVICES, THE PROVISION OF OR FAILURE TO PROVIDE SERVICES, OR FOR ANY INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, PRODUCTS, SERVICES AND RELATED GRAPHICS OBTAINED THROUGH THE EBOOK, OR OTHERWISE ARISING OUT OF THE USE OF OUR EBOOK, WHETHER BASED ON CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, EVEN IF BNI OR ANY OF ITS AGENTS, EMPLOYEES OR SUPPLIERS HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF DAMAGES.
BECAUSE SOME STATES/JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, THE ABOVE LIMITATION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.
IF YOU ARE DISSATISFIED WITH ANY PORTION OF OUR EBOOK, OR WITH ANY OF THESE TERMS OF USE, YOUR SOLE AND EXCLUSIVE REMEDY IS TO DISCONTINUE USING OUR EBOOK.
LIMITATION OF LIABILITY.
NOTWITHSTANDING ANY PROVISION TO THE CONTRARY, WHETHER CONTAINED IN THIS AGREEMENT OR OTHERWISE, IN NO EVENT SHALL BNI'S AGGREGATE LIABILITY HEREUNDER EXCEED THE AMOUNT OF THE FEES PAID HEREUNDER TO BNI IN THE SIX MONTHS PRIOR TO THE DATE ANY DAMAGES WERE INCURRED.
THIS LIMITATION SHALL APPLY TO ALL CAUSES OF ACTION AND CLAIMS IN THE AGGREGATE, AND SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF THE ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY LIMITED REMEDY.
Kids' Privacy.
Our eBook is intended for use by individuals 13 years of age or older.
Our eBook is not directed to children under the age of 13.
Subscribers under the age of 13 must use the assistance of a parent or guardian before they use or visit our eBook.
You agree to contact BNi immediately if you have knowledge that a child under the age of 13 has used the eBook or submitted Personal Information (as described in our Privacy Policy) to us, via our eBook or otherwise.
Errors, Corrections and Changes.
Occasionally there may be information on our eBook that contains typographical errors, inaccuracies, or omissions that may relate to product descriptions, pricing, and availability.
We reserve the right (and we will use commercially reasonable efforts) to correct any errors, inaccuracies or omissions.
Additionally, we reserve the right to change or update information at any time without prior notice.
Information & Content You Submit to Us.
Except as described in our Privacy Policy, by using the eBook, you agree that any information (except for purchase information as applicable), materials, suggestions, ideas or comments you send to us or any other third party using our eBook is not confidential.
By submitting any solicited or unsolicited information using our eBook, you grant to BNi and its affiliates an irrevocable and unrestricted license to use, modify, reproduce, transmit, display and distribute such materials, information, suggestions, ideas or comments for any purpose whatsoever, to the extent permitted by law.
Indemnity.
You agree to indemnify, defend and hold harmless BNi, its agents, employees, partners, affiliates, subsidiaries and suppliers from any liability, loss, claim and expense (including attorneys' reasonable fees as incurred) related to your violation of this Agreement or in connection with your use.
Third Party Sites & Links.
Our eBook may contain links to other sites that are not under our control ("Third-Party Site(s)").
We provide links solely for the convenience and information of our Subscribers.
We do not warrant or make any representation about the substance, quality, functionality, accuracy, fitness for a particular purpose, merchantability or any other representation about any Third-Party Site or its content.
A link to a Third-Party Site on our eBook does not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, approval or responsibility for any Third-Party Site.
We make no representation or warranty as to any products or services offered on any Third-Party Site.
The conditions of use and privacy policy of any Third-Party Site may differ substantially from the Terms of Use that apply to your use of our eBook.
Please review the conditions of use for all Third-Party Sites for more information about the terms and conditions that apply to your use of Third-Party Sites.
Applicable Law & Other Terms.
Our eBook is created, operated and controlled by BNi in California, in the United States of America.
Subscriber agrees that BNi and the eBook shall be deemed solely based in the State of California and the eBook shall be deemed a passive eBook that does not give rise to personal jurisdiction over BNi, either specific or general, in jurisdictions other than the State of California.
These Terms of Use are to be governed by and construed in accordance with the internal laws of the State of California, without regard for principles of conflicts of laws. Any civil action, claim, dispute or proceeding arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy shall be referred to final and binding arbitration, before a single arbitrator, under the commercial arbitration rules of the American Arbitration Association in San Diego County, California.
THEREFORE, YOU DO NOT HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO GO TO COURT TO ASSERT OR DEFEND YOUR RIGHTS AND YOU GIVE UP YOUR RIGHT TO PARTICIPATE IN OR BRING CLASS ACTIONS. BY USING THE EBOOK YOU AGREE TO STRICTLY ABIDE BY THESE RESTRICTIONS. ?You and BNi shall select the arbitrator, and if you and BNi are unable to reach agreement on selection of the arbitrator within thirty (30) days after the notice of arbitration is served, then the American Arbitration Association shall select the arbitrator.
Subscriber and BNi each agree to bear its own attorneys' fees and costs, in any arbitration proceeding.
Judgment upon any award rendered by the arbitrator shall be final, binding and conclusive upon Subscriber and BNi and each's respective administrators, executors, legal representatives, successors and assigns, and may be entered in any court of competent jurisdiction.
Should a dispute arise and should the arbitration provisions herein become inapplicable or unenforceable, or in any instance of any lawsuit between you and BNi, jurisdiction over and venue of any suit shall be exclusively in the state or federal courts sitting in Los Angeles County, California.
Notwithstanding the foregoing arbitration requirement, the parties may apply to such courts for immediate injunctive relief against the breach or threatened breach of this agreement, in addition to any other legal remedies that may be available.
Miscellaneous
If any part of this Agreement is determined to be invalid or unenforceable pursuant to applicable law including, but not limited to, the warranty disclaimers and liability limitations set forth above, then the invalid or unenforceable provision will be deemed superseded by a valid, enforceable provision that most closely matches the intent of the original provision and the remainder of the Agreement shall continue in effect.
Unless otherwise specified herein, this Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between Subscriber and BNi with respect to the eBook, and it supersedes all prior or contemporaneous communications and proposals, whether electronic, oral or written, between Subscriber and BNi with respect to the eBook.
A printed version of this Agreement and of any notice given in electronic form shall be admissible in judicial or administrative proceedings based upon or relating to this Agreement to the same extent and subject to the same conditions as other business documents and records originally generated and maintained in printed form.
×
Alert!
Your subscription may have expired.Please contact customer support.
expire link
×
Welcome Aboard ...
Thank you, [first name] for registering on Design Cost Data!
As a registered user you can try any Simpl•Est module FREE for 30 days.
Just click the Try it Free link below the module of your choice.
Privacy Policy
This privacy notice discloses the privacy practices for www.dcd.com. This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this web site. It will notify you of the following:
What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site, how it is used and with whom it may be shared
What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data
The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information
How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information
Information Collection, Use, and Sharing
We are the sole owners of the information collected on this site. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We partner with another party to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy. Your Access to and Control Over Information You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time.
You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the contact us form or phone number given on our website:
See what data we have about you, if any.
Change/correct any data we have about you.
Have us delete any data we have about you.
Express any concern you have about our use of your data.
Security
We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline. Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page. While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately via phone at 1.800.533.5680 or via email using our contact us form.
